Yulong Liang

Summary

Strong Computer Science background in software engineering and development cultivated by Georgia Tech. Proficient in trending coding and programming in multiple languages and software tools. Have proven experience and understanding in research, problem solving, design documentation, and data optimization.

Technical Skills

Programming Language: Python, Java, JavaScript, Julia, MATLAB, C, C++, CUDA, Golang, HTML5, CSS, MySQL Framework & Tools: React, Angular, D3, Node.js, Tableau, GitHub, OpenAPI, Linux, AWS, Docker, Kafka

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

Master of Science in Computational Science and Engineering

Aug 2022 - May 2024 GPA: 3.85/4

Georgia Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Science in Applied Physics, Minor in Computer Science, Highest Honor Distinction

Aug 2018 - May 2022 GPA: 3.83/4

Product Experience

TurboBe - GenAI Powered Immigration Application Agent | Co-Founder | Web

Aug 2024 – Present

- Architected and implemented a GenAI-based long-essay generation pipeline leveraging RAG and agent frameworks, incorporating content moderation and chain of thoughts
- Designed and deployed a scalable back-end system with **Django**, **REST**, and **Docker**. Reduced development time by 40% and successfully launched the application on Azure Cloud with a robust DevOps pipeline
- Built a front-end system using **React** with **10+** responsive web pages, integrating and testing APIs for seamless functionality and improved user experience

Work Experience

Tencent Jun 2021 – Aug 2021

Back-end Software Engineer

Beijing, China

- Built a back-end server for a cross-platform search system catering to up to 30,000 employees using Golang
- Developed and maintained a secure and efficient internal API with **Node.js** and **OpenAPI**, facilitating seamless data communication within the team service system over a **3**-month period
- Designed and implemented a reliable RPC service for the internet system, resulting in a 23% enhancement in real-time data update efficiency using tRPC-GO
- Conducted data cleaning and standardization for 20,000+ employees, contributing to the enhancement of the Tencent Information Security System's data quality and integrity using MySQL

Citibank May 2024 – Aug 2024

Full Stack Software Engineer

Atlanta, GA

- Developed a robust data management platform for a bank system using **Java Spring Boot** framework, achieving a **32**% reduction in average response time.
- Customized an informative front-end web page using **AngularJS**, implementing numerous UI enhancements that resulted in a **20**% increase in daily active users
- Built an advanced dataset system using MySQL and implemented over 50 unit tests, increasing test coverage by 40% and reducing bug rates by 25%

Georgia Institute of Technology, College of Computing

A

Aug 2022 – Jan 2024

Graduate Research Assistant

Atlanta, GA

- Utilize **Pytorch** to actively involve with current scientific machine learning and uncertainty quantification projects (plasma fusion and DESC stellarator optimization) led by Professor Peng Chen
- Apply **DESC library** to conduct force error balance analysis within the dynamic stellarator structure, generating perturbation results for pressure and rotational transform profiles with a sample size of up to **8000**
- Implemented a projected neural network using **Numpy** to train an input-output map in a 3D stellarator environment, Achieved an impressive reduction in force error for plasma fusion flow by 18%, demonstrating problem-solving and machine-learning skills

Institute of Physics, Chinese Academy of Science

Jun 2019 - Sep 2019

Research Assistant

Beijing, China

- Managed and trained 5 databases derived from electronic coherence in a 2D electronic spectroscopy experiment and produced graphical results with visualized data utilizing MATLAB and MySQL
- Formulated a comprehensive and professional experiment proposal, integrating the acquired numerical results to substantiate the research objectives with Latex and Tableau
- Designed and implemented an electronic signal detection tool utilizing **Java** and **LTspice**, leading to a 15% improvement in experiment response time and a 25% reduction in detection error